odds have gone up a lot, right? That the
lows in versus before the rally. I
suppose the the nail in the coffin to
the, you know, to the bare market would
be basically taking out the prior highs,
right? And I mean, historically, when
you're back above the 50we moving
average on, you know, multiple weekly
closes, the bare market is over. So now
it becomes a waiting game to figure out
if the low came earlier in the midterm
year than it normally does or if this is
just simply like a, you know, one of
those crazy rallies that gets you back
up near the prior high but doesn't fully
take it out. And we've had examples of
that before, right? I mean, it's kind of
some similar stuff happened in in uh
2018 uh 2015.
I think the hard thing with trying to
figure out if it's the if the low is in
or not is that you would expect if the
low were in for the rally to look
exactly like this, right? Like it
wouldn't look any different. Um uh so I
I I think that's where I am candidly is
just, you know, acceptance above the the
50we the prior high would in my opinion
be the nail in the coffin for the for
the bare market. Uh but I mean until
that until that comes to pass there's
always a reason to to speculate and and
if you look I was looking at all the all
the indicators some of the indicators
have fully reset right like the supply
and profit and loss um if if you look at
that if you look at any type of the the
weekly RSI the monthly RSI you could
argue that all looks like it's
completely reset but then you look at
other things like the the realized price
and the balance price and the MBRVZ
score those don't really seem like they
fully reset. So, it's one of those
things where kind of like at the highs,
like, you know, we didn't really go all
the way up. Uh, and it left people
wondering maybe the same thing's
happening now. Um, but I I don't really
feel like we I I don't feel like I can
say with confidence until until we get
through kind of the next pullback and
then it prints a higher low and and
acceptance above the prior high would I
think kind of dictate whether the low is
in or not. Regardless, as history has
taught us, DCAing throughout the second
half of the midterm year is normally the
way to be successful with with Bitcoin.
And hopefully this time is is no
different.
>> Okay. Okay. So, yeah, that's um that's a
great that's a great sort of round up
from a from a technical perspective if
you like. Nick, what do you think? And
and what do you think from a kind of
fundamental perspective as well? I mean,
kind of what's what's really changed on
that side of the equation over the last
week or so?
>> Well, yeah. I mean, it's it's good to
look at the historical analogs to try
and draw um you know, estimations as to
what could have happened and where we
could go and whether it was a low or
not. I mean, Ben mentioned some of them.
I mean, some of the other onchain stuff
that we had more than 50% of the supply
in a loss. We had long-term holder
accumulation prior to this. We saw the
realized P&L at a 43month low on the
onchain indicators. But I think the
catalyst that drove us up right now was
idiosyncratic outside of just historical
norms. And that was what happened uh
with the Fed Treasury buybacks, right?
And that catalyzed the move in the not
just Bitcoin but also in gold. So these
these trades around the debasement trade
and uh that's not something that has
happened necessarily before in in
Bitcoin's history in terms of like a
treasury operation like this. I mean
there was operation twist back in 2011
but that was when Bitcoin was just in
its nency. So this obviously drove
liquidity drove Bitcoin through this his
historic melt up and short squeeze.
there was a lot of short position and we
saw massive liquidations and
subsequently obviously when price
rallies it's the most important catalyst
for more interest in interest in bitcoin
in this particular case we saw ETF
accumulation indeed last week we had the
the highest accumulation uh since last
year end of since October last year so
in that sense I think that it was one of
it was a a market that was at its lows
and it just needed some sort of a
catalyst to to basically just push it to
in this explosive rally up. I do think
though that we are going to have a
retracement as there is profit taken. I
don't think it's going to be a straight
line up. Uh but I do think that the lows
we saw in June were the lows for this
particular cycle. Either way, as Ben
mentioned, it's good to just DCA into
Bitcoin in an election year because on
average, you're going to have got you at
an attractive price into we to to where
we go towards our our high could be next
year, for example.
>> Yeah. Interesting. Yeah, there's Yeah, I
guess the short squeeze was was really
sort of what what propelled the rocket
fuel, didn't it? you know, that I guess
the the bond buyback announcement kind
of got it off the launch pad and then it
was supercharged by um by short
squeezes. And I've been trying to sort
of look around and see if there's
anything sort of more fundamentally
changed. I mean, there is spot buying. I
think we touched on this in last week's
live stream. There is spot buying from
the ETFs. I think the ETFs have taken in
something in the region of $3 billion
just in August. Um and obviously there's
still a few days of August left. So, you
know, this isn't just a short squeeze
happening. There is buying. There is
buying, you know, on spot going on
underneath that. Um, I did find
something quite interesting because
like, you know, we've been talking at
various points over the year about some
of the things that have arguably been
holding Bitcoin back uh that have acted
as, you know, a bit of a headwind. One
of which was the quantum threat. You
know, I think a lot of people really
started to get concerned about that.
There was a lot of talk around that.
Obviously, we've been seeing uh quite a
few kind of quantum developments make
headlines across this year. Um I did
actually see I thought I'd share this. I
saw this on Twitter, a post from uh a
post from the block uh talking about how
the first quantum resistant Bitcoin
transaction has apparently been
successfully executed. Now, I'm not
going to pretend that that is, you know,
that is some kind of catalyst all on its
own because I don't think it is. But um
I think maybe that points to uh to to
the fact that some uh development is
going on uh you know in terms of of
making Bitcoin quantum resistance. So if
that particular worry can be uh you know
can be dialed down or or even removed
then you know that would remove a major
headwind for uh for Bitcoin going
forward. But you know kind of other than
that yeah it not an awful lot has
fundamentally changed. Trump sort of
came out, didn't he? Um said the US
could buy uh the US government could buy
uh Bitcoin. Um you know, I think most
people sort of took that with something
of a grain of salt. Um as as you have to
do with anything, he says, but um yeah,
interesting. Okay. Well, let's move on
and and talk about the macro uh thing
then because I want to I want to get
your
your impressions of these Bessant bond
buybacks uh that he's been doing. I
mean, is this is this going to work for
one thing? Um, Nick, can I start with
you on this one?
>> Well, if his intent was to bring down
interest rates in the 30-year debt, uh,
it didn't really work because it kind of
roundtrip after the intervention almost
immediately. Uh, I think that, you know,
the major structural issue is the size
of the US debt and interfering in the
market and trying to uh, use what is
supposed to be an emergency measure.
these liquid liquidity provision, these
buybacks is what they're supposed to be
used for. And he wanted to use it
because he thought that the interest
rate in the markets right now does not
reflect the quote fundamentals of the US
debt. I mean, the fundamentals are it's
$40 trillion in debt. You've got $1.37
trillion in yearly interest payments on
that debt. And uh I think that the
market prices that in and it it then
offer it's willing to accept a bid for
the yield and that's what the the debt
will clear at. And I think um now what
you have is a situation where the market
has seen that there's a particular level
that Scott Bessant is sensitive to and
will react to and you have the situation
where Bon vigilantes could accelerate
selling if they believe that the
treasury is panicking and that then of
course leads to yields spiking higher
and it kind of backfires completely. Uh
and you know I mean there were people
who came out many bond fund managers and
indeed even his mentor uh Mr. Stanley
Rucker Miller came out and said that
this was a this was an ill- advised move
uh to do this for the to interfere in
the Treasury market and to try and
basically they issuing more debt.
They're still issuing debt to buy this
because they're issuing treasury bills
so the shorterdated stuff to buy back
the long end and basically like adjust
this is why they say it's analogist to
operation twist on the yield curve. Uh
but yeah, I mean it's probably seems to
have had the same impact as the Japanese
yen intervention 3 weeks ago or a month
ago. Uh so he's definitely a very active
Treasury SE secretary. Indeed, probably
the most active that they've been that
we've had for quite some time. indeed
harking back to his hedge fund days
trying to play instead of playing with
uh the assets under management of his
investors. He's playing with the entire
Treasury general account which he's also
said he could potentially use as a
potential uh fund to buy to fund these
buybacks. But uh yeah, I think that it's
counterintuitive and uh the market is
reacting, you know, correctly to it.
>> Yeah. Ben, what do you think? I mean, is
there is as far as as far as you know,
is there really anything that that Scott
Bessant or indeed, you know, maybe even
anyone else can actually do about this
that about this 40 trillion wall of
debt? I mean, is is all of this just for
show and really, you know, it's just
rearranging debt chairs on the Titanic?
>> Yeah, I mean, the debt's only going to
go up. I think that's been more or less
established. Um, you know, if you look
at, uh, if you think about what caused
the long end of the yield curve to get
to where it was, what they're doing
doesn't fix any of those problems. And
you could you could argue it would just
make them worse. I mean, in some ways,
what they're doing could theoretically
be seen as inflationary. Um, and I I
think it's I mean I I'm I'm a big
believer in like just letting the
markets like do what they're going to do
and not try to interfere with them
because while interfering in the short
term might put a band-aid on things,
eventually the band's probably going to
get get ripped off. And when that
happens, it leads to worse outcomes than
if they had just kind of let it unfold
naturally. My my guess is that Kevin
Worsh So Kevin Worsh is going to be
speaking tomorrow at Jackson Holt. Um
I'm I would guess that he might be asked
about what Drunken Miller said. And I
I'm really curious as to what his
response is going to be. Uh whether he
will agree with Drunken Miller and be
like, "Yeah, maybe he has a point." Or
whether he'll uh push back. to some
degree what it what it feels like a lot
of the people in the administration are
doing is just they're kind of like
saying a lot of things to just kind of
see what works um kind of like gauge the
market reaction from what they're saying
and then half the time I mean I don't
know about with with this specifically
it seems like they probably would follow
through with it but there have been
times throughout the last year or two
where you know things are just said as
like oh let's just see how the market
reacts but then they don't actually
follow through with it you know and I
think that's happened many many times so
I I'd like to see what what Wars has to
say tomorrow at at Jackson Hole and and
if he's going to give any guidance as
to, you know, will they will they raise
rates because I mean the argu one of the
arguments is like the the thing one of
the things they could do to help the
long end of the yield curve which would
probably help it more than what they're
doing is just raising interest rates. Um
because if you raise rates that would
theoretically affect growth in the short
term which then would probably make the
markets not as fearful about inflation.
the the yield the longer the yield curve
going up is just an artifact at this
point of people believing that they're
just simply going to let inflation run
hot and they're not going to do anything
to stop it. So if if they want to make
the case that they're going to actually
do something they need to they need to
raise rates. Um and I mean the market
thinks they're going to raise rates
before the end of the year. Uh but we'll
see. I mean that that changes all the
time.
>> Yeah. It's also interesting to the
degree where Walsh has said he wants to
no forward guidance. He wants to be he
wants to let the market price things as
they should be and he I think in his
last FOMC he said he'd rather lean on
like the long end of the curve to
basically tamp down inflation and now
you have Bessant coming out who's been
very vocal
the opposite of of not giving forward
guidance about the fundamental uh yield
it should be and trying to and trying to
suppress it. So they're working the
>> [laughter]
>> They're contradicting each other to a
degree and they're supposed to be
coordinated. I mean, they were both
employed and and proteges of Draen
Miller coincidentally as well.
>> Well, now they can just point the finger
at each other if things go poorly.
>> That's true. Someone else to blame.
>> Yeah.
>> Isn't at the end of the day, isn't that
what politics is all about? Just finding
just finding someone else to blame. Um
it will be interesting, won't it, to to
to see what Walsh has to say because I
mean he's you know he said that forward
guidance isn't isn't his thing and he's
not going to do it. So perhaps you
perhaps they might be able to draw him
on on what on what Draen Miller and
other says because um I mean I guess in
a way they are although they should be
you they should be pulling in the same
direction Walsh and Bessant I guess you
could argue that they're they really
want opposite things because Walsh wants
to keep inflation under control whereas
Bessant you know if he's got any sense
probably realizes that the only way uh
that this $40 trillion of debt gets
dealt with in the long term is by
inflating it away. Like, okay, they're
resting their hopes on the on the AI
productivity boom, which may or may not
come. That feels like a little bit of a
Hail Mary. Um, so the only other option
after that is is inflation to to devalue
it. But, um, I don't know, maybe I'm
reading too much into it. Um, I want to
talk about I want to talk about how you
invest in in in an environment like
this. We many would say that we're
moving into an era of financial
repression, of increased inflation, of
debt monetization. Um, and it's, you
know, it's kind of hard to argue with
that at times like this. So, how do you
how do you think about investing uh
going into, you know, looking at that
sort of future? Um, Ben, [clears throat]
what would be your thoughts?
>> I mean, I'm doing more or less what I've
always done, but hard assets for sure.
Um, you know, I mean, you look at gold
off the lows, like gold has also had a
strong rally. Not as much as as what
Bitcoin had off the lows, but for the
size of gold's market cap, it had a it's
had a pretty impressive rally off the
lows. I think it was like 20% or so or
almost 20, whereas Bitcoin was 40. So, I
think hard asset investing is one way
because the the argument is they're
they're just simply going to continue to
print. They're going to try to inflate
the debt away and when that happens, you
want to own hard assets. And the other
thing is just buying I mean I do what I
always do every month and that's buying
index funds. Um because [clears throat]
again the argument is that you know the
it's it's so hard like trying to time
the stock market and so like I've always
just kind of bought index funds.
Recently I I've I've sort of tended more
towards international funds over like I
I've I think for the last like 1015
years I was always 2/3 domestic
one-third international. So like 2/3
basically you know a market a fund that
tracks the US and then one/ird
international.
But uh over the last like several months
it's more like 50/50 you know where it's
not as tilted. And one of the reasons
for that is just because I think there's
a lot more uncertainty now. I mean,
there's not there's no forward guidance.
Who knows what Trump's going to say any
any given day. Um, it's just there's
more more uncertainty. So, there's all
that. And of course, you know, Bitcoin
is is always there
a a pretty good buy in, you know, in
near the end of midterm years. Um, so I
I think that's the way to go and, you
know, it's worked out for the long haul.
And I I will argue that it probably will
continue to work out as we go and and
assuming this time's not different. Now,
at some point, they run the risk of of a
larger liquidation event if they keep
trying to put band-aids on things rather
than just letting things because
basically what happens is it it allows,
you know, more and more leverage to
build up in a system than just letting
the market play out, right? Like letting
the market do whatever the market's
going to do. So eventually, but I mean,
good luck timing that, you know, who
knows when that's going to could be next
year, could be five years from now,
could be 15 years from now, I don't
know.
>> Um, but I I think any any investor knows
that they will experience those draw
downs, but it's not a reason to to sit
out of the market waiting for it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Very true. Nick, what what
are your thoughts?
>> Yeah, it's an interesting thought there,
Ben, around your just coming to your
point around the foreign equities as
well. I mean, I assume also part of it
is is dollar weakness potentially. Then
you have returns, foreign returns are
slightly higher than you would get on US
equ onshore equities, right?
>> Yeah. I mean, this year I've actually
been bullish on the dollar, which it's
kind of interesting because the dollar's
flat this year so far. Uh but yeah, I
think the dollar will probably turn back
down over the next like couple of years
after, you know, and I think that'll be
be the case for why foreign investments
will do well. Yeah, financial repression
that's going to be especially you know
with monetization of the debt that's
very bearish for the dollar. Um in terms
of what I would think for in in this
world of financial repression uh you
mentioned gold and bitcoin uh but I
think real assets like commodities,
energy, infrastructure,
farmland. So anything that where the
intrinsic value is not denominated in
fiat. Um, I would also think about
potentially like shorter duration bonds
or treasury in inflation protected
securities or tips if you must hold any
sort of fixed income assets. Um, and
then maybe some selective equities. So,
companies that have strong pricing power
and can you know increase prices if the
cost of everything else is increasing.
Um, so and that's in the equity side.
And then potentially the things to avoid
are cash, right? and then longdated
bonds. So, yeah, I think that's the
portfolio for the financial repression
portfolio.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Energy energy has been great.
That's been one of my better investments
this year, honestly.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And and I mean, the long-term
thesis for that is is pretty
straightforward, isn't it? I um
>> I read just just recently that I think
at the moment um the the the ratio of
actual of assets held in cash the um the
amount of the amount of cash being held
is is at record lows. You know people
are people are sort of basically allin
uh on the market. So I'll have to I
think that was in the finance bureau
newsletter uh the other day. So um yeah
it seems it seems people are are very
much very much wise to this. Okay, let's
talk about one of the uh one of the big
winners of the last few years um that
reported earnings uh yesterday. This was
of course Nvidia. Um now it would be a
bit of an understatement to say that
expectations were high for Nvidia's
earnings yesterday. Um it really did
feel like the whole AI trade was kind of
hanging on it and actually Nvidia's
stock had been on quite a quite a bad
run. Had been sold off quite a lot. Um
however uh the earnings came yesterday
and they were they were stellar really
96.2 billion dollars in revenue um
beating expectations and up I over 100%
year onear which is just crazy there
were still concerns there were still um
you know this whole sort of talk of
circular financing within the AI complex
if you like. Um, so what was your what
were your reads of it and what do what
does Nvidia's continued strength for now
mean for the wider AI trade? Nick, do
you want to start us off on this? No.
The show goes on, right? [laughter]
You know, it's like the, you know, Chuck
Prince back in 2008, the CEO of Cityroup
when he said that as long as the music
is playing and everyone's dancing, you
keep dancing. That is until it's like a
game of musical chairs and there's no
more chairs to sit down on. Yeah. I
think in this particular case, yeah,
look, I mean, the numbers beat
expectations. There there was one that
didn't, and that was the Q um the next
quarter guidance was $108 billion
guidance um for the next quarter. Uh and
the markets were expecting slightly
higher and then immediately sold off.
But then after that, the C CFO came out
with projected revenue for next year up
70%. Right? This is for a $4 trillion
company. So this is far above the 45%
analyst expectations and that's why the
stock rallied in the pre-market uh and
extended its gains. So right now it
seems as if you know the uh the AI trade
is is still in full swing. Uh Nvidia is
printing. Uh there is massive demand for
their chips. The margin is slightly
compressed but that's just because of
the um the memory itself memory
shortages. Um so I think that this is
why the stock is up and the and I think
the whole market is breathing a sigh of
relief and many AI stocks themselves
have picked up on that. But the
questions still remain especially the
questions around circular financing uh
and indeed for example this $500 billion
securitized data center package where
they are basically backstopping the debt
for all their customers to buy chips
that they manufacture. And this whole
question of the circular financing loop
continues. Uh and that's there's many
people who point it out for things like
they've extended out the uh invoice term
for a lot of their revenue which
questions around you know are they
basically further financing their their
customers to be able to buy their chips.
So there's still many questions on the
table but for now the music goes on.
>> Thanks Nick. Yeah Ben what did you make
of it? I mean, did were you were you
surprised that Nvidia beat expectations
so comprehensively gi given perhaps how
high the bar was or you know was this
something you were expecting? What did
you make of it all? I
>> feel like it's consistently beat
expectations for years for the most
part. I mean occasionally there might be
a number like Nick said where it's not
as you know it doesn't quite do it but I
mean guidance has been strong. I I'm
actually I'm pretty simple with this. I
I believe that the the AI bubble goes on
uh at least until Open AI IPOs, you
know, so [clears throat] I I don't think
it'll end before then. So, and I don't
think they're going to IPO until 2027 is
is what I because I think they're I
think they're chasing a$1 trillion
valuation. Um which would I think be
easier to achieve.
>> You know, when you get into the trillion
dollar valuations, I think it's they
they want to wait a little bit longer.
Um, but Anthropic I think might be IPO
might be IPOing within the next month or
two. So that might be, you know, a
short-term um,
catalyst for [clears throat] crypto like
money going into the crypto space right
now might be going over back into the AI
trade. Kind of like you remember when
SpaceX IPOed like every market including
the S&P was kind of struggling while
every all the money just went into
SpaceX. So I think
>> at a $2 trillion valuation, I mean it's
going to suck the liquidity out of
everything if they're going to get
because they're trying to target a $2
trillion listing, which is more than
SpaceX. Uh and they also believe their
get this their total addressable market
in terms of revenue is $30 trillion.
[laughter]
That's their expectations. So they got
big hopes.
>> Well, you have to remember in 20 years
$30 trillion might be like5 trillion
dollars today.
>> [laughter]
>> That's true.
And as we say, what's a few trillion
dollars among friends, right?
[clears throat]
>> We'll all we'll be we'll be peeling off
we'll be peeling off a trillion dollar
note at the uh at the supermarket to pay
for groceries by that point,
>> right? Yeah. Exactly.
>> Yeah. Um yes, it is interesting to watch
anthropic kind of really go for it,
isn't it? Because yeah, I think I think
you're right, Ben. Open AIS does appear
to have been pushed back to last year.
And of course the company itself you
know there seems to be not all seems to
be uh sunshine and rainbows there given
how many people have been quitting. you
know, quite a lot of quite a lot of
executives have kind of walked out and,
you know, when you think they're they're
in line for this, you know, massive IPO
payout and they're kind of cashing in
their chips and leaving early, you do
sort of think, okay, and you know,
meanwhile, Anthropic sort of really
going for it all while I think there's
actually sort of I've seen quite a lot
of criticism of of Claude recently, how
it hasn't been performing as, you know,
as well. And of course there's all this
question of uh of suddenly these Chinese
models being able to do it all for a
fraction of the price. So yeah, although
things do look, you know, although you
get an earnings call like Nvidia and you
think, yeah, this this this dance can go
on a bit longer, it it's sort of the
more you think, well, yeah, when it does
eventually when the music does
eventually stop, it really is going to
be some something of a bloodbath.
>> Let's Let's see. It's uh it's going to
be interesting, that's for sure. Now,
speaking of AI, I want to I want to
finish up with a slightly more
philosophical point, if you like. Um let
me just share my screen here. So, we
we've alluded to this earlier on in the
in the stream a couple of times. So, um
Stanley Ducken Miller, the investing
legend, um has been has come out came
out in the Wall Street Journal with some
criticism of um Scott Bessants's uh
Scott Bessant's bond strategy. Bessant I
think is a sort of old acolyte of
drunken millers. Certainly, you know,
certainly they they go way back. Um but
I don't really want to talk about that
side of it because I think we've covered
it. But um it was pretty clear I I
remember thinking this the moment I read
it. It was clear that it was uh written
by written with AI and sure enough he
was challenged on this and Draen Miller
came out and he said, "Well, I write
everything using AI now." So, I mean,
this is this has sparked a lot of
debate, and I'm just interested to to to
know what you guys make of it. Like, is
that okay? I mean, you know, is it is it
okay? You you you have you have a page,
you have a column in the Wall Street
Journal. Say whatever you like. Is that
okay to be using AI to write that? Or is
it, you know, natural? Is it is it a
good way to get it written and save
time? I I'm just curious to see what you
guys think. And you know obviously this
is a debate that that is uh that can go
very deep but um yeah curious to know
your thoughts Nick what about you?
Yeah, I mean firstly like I from the
first paragraph in I could see that uh
wow did he really get Claude to write up
his Wall Street Journal editorial and I
thought how would the Wall Street
Journal allow this to be published
without the basics basic checkin but as
it turns out like mostly opinion pages
they publish as is as I understand it
separate from the news desk so they
thought well even if they did read it
and they thought this was written with
the assistance of AI they still chose to
publish and they defended it. Uh and the
notion being that look I mean AI is now
being used as a ghost writing tool for
many busy exe executives, investors and
public figures and it is accelerating.
And is it okay to normalize it now? I
mean like Draken Miller said his most
the most embarrassing thing for him was
that many people had said to him they
were so surprised at how well written
his opinion piece was. Maybe those were
people who didn't identify the AI isms
in it. Uh, but I I think for me it took
a bit of the shine off of it a little
bit because I I you how do you know how
much of that was just the writing
assistance versus the actual thinking
and thought that went into the actual
article and the analogies used and that?
So I mean I'm in two minds about it to
be honest.
>> Yeah. Ben, what about you? Because you
know we've all tal we've talked on this
stream before Y, me, Rob, and Nick. you
know, how we all I think we all find AI
really useful. You know, we're not in
the sort of anti- AAI camp at all, I
don't think. But is this a step too far
or is this just perfectly chill and and
we should stop ftting about it?
>> You know, I have a lot of uh developers
for into the cryptoverse right on the
platform and I actively encourage them
to use AI because
>> but I mean this is for writing code,
right? This is for writing code. Um,
yeah. And I mean it it it it it makes
them all a lot more productive, I think.
Um, which is good
>> when it comes to writing. I mean, I
think it's one of those things where
initially it's kind of like pushed back
upon, but in five or 10 years, I
wouldn't be surprised if like it's
pretty much what is the norm for a lot
of people. And and by that point, I I
don't I don't even know if we'll even
it. You know, you know how like when the
president gives a talk um no one believe
well maybe with Trump that's different
but most presidents speech speak no one
believes that they actually wrote the
speech right someone else wrote it for
them but they're getting credit like
when they say something they're like you
can you can basically say that is their
opinion because they're saying it even
though we know they didn't write it this
is what they're saying and so we kind of
take it for this is what Trump said or
this is what Biden said or Obama or
whoever.
Even though we know they had uh someone
write it for them, I my guess is that
this is what's going to happen with AI
is people are going to be like, "Yeah,
like we know it was written by AI." But
with that said, we're just going to
start assigning it. Like this is Drunken
Miller's opinion whether he wrote it
with AI or not. I think that's kind of
where things are headed. I don't know if
it's truly his opinion, but as as far
as, you know, what we talk about and and
stuff, I think people will just start
accepting that people will use AI and
that if they express if they write
something and they put it out there, if
they put their name on it, that's
basically just being assigned to what
what they think. And uh no different
than what a you know, a speech writer
would be for a politician.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I think
>> Sorry, Nick. Go on.
>> Yeah. No, I think as long as they take
the time to read through it and vet that
they totally agree with everything with
everything that's been said in the same
vein that a script writer would give you
a script to or to to basically go and
present as long as they actually take
the time to read it and not come back a
day later when there was some sort of a
and say, "Oh, no, that was just the AI
that wrote that. I didn't really mean to
say that. I didn't really agree with it.
It was just the AI." Yeah.
>> Yeah. That that won't be that won't be a
good defense for people. Like you can't
just say, "I used AI." Like I people
would would hate that.
>> It's kind of like when you're the
lawyers that that go in front of the
judge that site cases that never
existed, you know, like you you you
can't just claim ignorance and and that
you didn't have time to review the AI
the AI slop, right? You have to you have
to read it and and if you're going to
put it out there, like you can't say
that, well, I just didn't proofread it.
>> Yeah. It's it's interesting that that's
a very interesting point as well, Ben,
you make about speech writers because
yeah, like you know, this this has never
been this has never been something
that's covered up like, you know, speech
writers are have been an acknowledged uh
staff, you know, staffer in in the White
House and, you know, administrations
everywhere for years. like we know they
exist and and yeah, when when a
president or a prime minister makes a
speech um yeah we we know that they
probably didn't write all of it or you
know maybe they were involved at some it
to some degree but yeah they were
written by they are just basically there
to
>> to deliver it. Um, and that's that
that's a very interesting point and I
mean because my my sort of thoughts on
this were like, well, okay, yeah, it's
fine to write something, you know, maybe
if you're writing an internal memo or if
you're writing code or if you're
writing, you know, if you need to to
write up some, you know, some legal
stuff, uh, anything that sort of, um, is
going to be time consuming and AI can
just do it faster and more efficiently.
But I sort of my thoughts were it's like
well if you're in the Wall Street
Journal you know this is quite a
privileged spot that you have like you
know not everyone gets to gets to air
their opinions in in the Wall Street
Journal or you know the mainstream press
if you like. And
>> I was sort of thinking like well
>> yeah it seems like if if [laughter]
you're going to have that sort of
platform then you really should sort of
you shouldn't be delegating this to AI.
But then it it came into my mind that,
you know, I I don't think it's so
prevalent now, but in the past, um,
newspapers in particular would would
have teams of of subeditors, um, who
quite often would take a journalist's
piece and completely rewrite it, you
know, and and they were the kind of
unsung heroes of of the press because
the journalists, okay, would they would
go out and get the information and uh,
you know, they would put the story
together. But, you know, I've heard I've
heard tales of quite a lot of
journalists who, you know, who really
weren't actually that good at the
writing side of it. And in the old days,
they would phone through to the uh to
the sub editor's desk, dictate what
they'd written, and then the subs would
would rewrite it. But, of course, you
know, for a long time now, newspapers
have been cutting back on that side of
things, and, you know, the the internet
has changed all that, and now it seems
like AI is the kind of, you know, is the
big subeditor. But yeah, I I kind of
think it's all right in some parts, but
if this become if if the future that
you're talking about becomes like yeah,
most of today's Wall Street Journal was
written with AI, then obviously, you
know, the a AI is going to keep feeding
that back into itself. So, we're going
to end up with quite possibly this doom
loop where AI just is trained on on what
AI has already written. And you know,
let's face it, okay, some sometimes it
comes out with some with some pretty
good stuff, but quite a lot of the time,
you know, it really is slop. And that's
what I worry about. I kind of feel there
should perhaps be a line, you know, and
if you have this platform, then uh then
maybe you should maybe you should uh
make it a bit more human. Anyhow, this
is a this is a debate we could have for
a a very long time. Um before we go, I
just want to uh I I just want to flag up
a few of the comments here. There's some
interesting ones here. Um, Mktar is
saying 15th of September September, the
Clarity Act closure vote has a high
probability of failure. This could
trigger selloff and market can go down.
I mean, yeah, the Clarity Act has sort
of um gone out of our consciousness a
bit, but it is uh you know, it is still
a thing. Um, uh, what else have we
>> priced I think it's priced to fail. I
think honestly it'll be a catalyst if
it's passes and if so, more for alcoins
than Bitcoin.
Yeah. Interesting. Interesting. Um, what
else have we got? Uh, I quite like this
quote from Dr. Ivo BTC. When the music's
over, turn off the lights.
[laughter] When it all goes dark, that's
when we'll know. Um, and an interesting
question here to finish off with. Why
does Guy look like a Mossad agent? Do I
look like Do I look like a Mossad agent?
>> What would a Mossad agent look like?
That's an interesting question.
>> And why would they be on a live stream
about crypto? Listen 1984. I can't I
can't speak to that at all. All I'd say
is just keep away from the window. All
right.
>> Well, he says you look like a Mosad
agent, but he's the one with the all CNI
as the uh as the profile picture. So, we
interesting.
>> Yeah,
>> big brother's watching you.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Absolutely. Okay, Ben,
Nick, thank you very much for today,
chaps. Uh it's been great to catch up
with you. Lots to talk about. Uh, next
week I think we're going to be on Rob's
channel, but I will we'll uh confirm
that nearer the time. Um, but great to
see you both and thanks for joining and
thank you everyone for watching.
>> Likewise. Have a great time, guys.
>> Cheers all. Goodbye.